this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC Radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
softball listen up software engineers
what was the last time you proposed a
product change that was really listened
to how often does your code shift to
production same day within minutes when
was the last time you actually wanted to
go to work
ed ultimate software this could be your
new normal and with offices in Florida
Georgia in California what are you
waiting for visit ultimate software comm
slash careers today and start making a
difference tomorrow ultimate software
people first welcome everyone to
software engineering radio today hi my
name's Kim Carter I'll be your host for
the day today we've got Scott Piper
Scott has a decade of experience in
cybersecurity having previously worked
at the NSA as a developer for commercial
security products and is the director of
security for a start-up India focuses on
improving the security of AWS
environments as an independent
consultant welcome to the show Scott hey
thanks for having me
we've had shows on the modern
cloud-based platform in 2014 with Adam
Cockcroft it was show number 216 and
we've had a show on docker security with
a Diego moniker that was show number 290
now there are some relevant articles
from I Triple E Computer Society on
today's topic cloud security and
security challenges in cloud today we're
going to be discussing in cloud security
it's just got to start off with some
basic questions we're moving to the
cloud our servers compute storage and
many other physical aspects have now
become abstract concepts there's a
software engineer what thoughts do you
have on how we need to change your
approach to security when moving to the
cloud Oh a lot of it honestly is it's a
lot of the same concepts but you just
have to learn how to apply them slightly
differently so so one of the things that
US and other cloud providers talk about
it it's kind of a shared responsibility
model and so what you have to understand
going in is is there are some things
that your cloud provider will take care
of for you and there's some things that
that you still need to take care of for
yourself or need to focus more on and so
some examples of that is you know you
could use different types of services
that for example like load balancing
services might do SSL termination or
something like that for you so you're
not gonna have to worry about you know
updating as open SSL on those different
services however you still make sure
that any endpoints that you have behind
those you know that you still look for
and take care of any type of sequel
injection or cross-site scripting or
other types of issues like that
so so it's just kind of understanding
where your responsibilities lie and
where the cloud vendors responsibilities
lie yeah
can you explain what the shared
responsibility model is and how it's
supposed to work and what sort of
misconceptions are around it yeah so so
it basically just means that that there
there's gonna be some things for example
you know the the physical security of
the environment you know you don't have
to you know you are not going to be
responsible for trying to take any
precautions to try and protect the you
know actual physical data centers of
your cloud provider however there you
know the software that gets installed
onto the the instances that that
provider provides to you you still have
to take care of that yourself and so so
you have to understand for the different
services that you're using from them
where your responsibilities end and
where there's begin and so you know it
becomes just important to try and make
make note of that as you're going
through and setting things up and
determining how much time you're gonna
end up spending in different areas so in
terms of the shared responsibility model
what aspects of security is the CSP or a
cloud service provider actually
responsible for again it's it's going to
depend on the different services that
you're using so you know for example if
you're using you know AWS is easy to
serves that's going to be basically
providing you with a VM instance that
you can install software on and so
you're gonna be responsible for updating
the operating system on there and
updating any of the software that you're
running on there but if you're using
something like a tus lambda that's going
to be a service that all you're going to
be doing is running code on there so
that's gonna be and so in that case
you're not gonna be responsible for the
operating system or updating you know
some of the libraries that happen behind
the scenes but the libraries that you
put on there yourself or the code that
you put on there yourself you're gonna
have to make sure that you update that
so I guess due to the scale of the size
of most of them a large CS piece in like
they generally have their own security
teams and that sort of thing
now they do actually take care of a lot
of stuff that we used to have to take
care of ourselves right before the
migration to the cloud exactly yeah so
so I mean they're there there's a ton of
different service offerings that they're
providing and like I said you know one
of the biggest ones that's just gonna be
across the board for all the different
services that you're using it's just
gonna be that that physical security
that you're not gonna have to worry
about so you know having a data center
and having you know potentially guards
Manning it you know 24/7 and video
surveillance around it and the processes
and procedures for destroying hard
drives that have come to end of life and
things like that you know your cloud
service provider is gonna take care of
those for you but then when it comes to
things like patching and upgrading
there's kind of a give-and-take and you
have to you have to realize which
services you're using is going to be
dependent on which of those
responsibilities you have so what do you
see is the highest risks and handing
everything either to CS pays I think the
kind of the biggest danger is just the
realization that that in your historic
data centers that you controlled and
maintained yourself one you potentially
had more visibility into into what
happened there and and you had more
ability to to set the your own rules for
yourself whereas when you move to a
cloud service provider you know they're
setting all those rules for you and in
some cases you know they they might not
be the same rules or as good rules is
you would have liked
for the most part you know a lot of the
rules that they've said and practices
and procedures that they're following
are gonna be at a higher level than you
would be able to maintain yourself and
so so that's you know one of one of the
big things that another big issue is
just that historically in your own data
center if something was to be exposed
publicly to the internet that was
probably gonna require you know firewall
changes which might mean someone
actually having to physically go to the
to a data center and potentially plug
things in actual you know physically
manually plug things in between boxes in
order to make that happen or at least
you know physically go to that data
center in order to log into the console
and make those changes and and so that's
that's kind of the biggest difference is
now with the cloud you know things can
get expose Pollak Lee just with a click
of the button it's very simple it's very
easy and so you know with with that ease
comes those problems as well and that
you can accidentally make these changes
you know or become so easy that you know
someone that that doesn't understand
what they're doing could potentially
make those things it publicly accessible
and so as an example of this we've seen
that you know every week a new company
comes out that's been a victim of an s3
bucket on Amazon that's been publicly
exposed because there there's a single
button that you click on there just to
say make this publicly you know world
accessible and it becomes available to
everybody yeah yeah yeah I think your
project our floors is a great example of
here developers and engineers can
actually get better at doing this stuff
as well which we'll discuss um closer
toward that I mean to the show yeah so
here's what we're trying to protect as
software engineers in the organizations
we work for changed much from the exodus
of on-premise to the cloud and of so
here so I won't say that that it's been
so much a change of on-premise to the
cloud but just a change as to how kind
of everybody is approaching a lot of
software development and in operations
these days and specifically that they're
becoming more blended and part of that
is due to the cloud making that easier
because now you can you know you can
acquire servers with clicks of the
button or with
just scripting it in writing code to
accomplish that so so that become it
becomes a lot more blended with a you
know DevOps movement that happening and
you know a lot of the reason why the
DevOps movement has happened has been
because you know people's time has been
freed up in order to accomplish this
blend of activities as opposed to having
to be siloed into specific skills yeah
yes so we're still trying to protect
their own customer data and that sort of
thing right so that hasn't really
changed our move has it no I mean a lot
of their you know your same goals and a
lot of your same practices you know also
apply to the cloud in different ways
it's just kind of the the biggest things
around it have really just been you know
now you can use things like you know
terraform CloudFormation or other type
of scripting technologies in order to
bring up new instances change firewall
settings and be able to make those
changes via simple scripts and simple CL
eyes so how do we need to adjust their
thinking so that our security focuses in
the right areas and in here should our
focus have changed I think it mostly
becomes you know now that now that there
aren't certain things that you need to
worry about because of the shared
responsibility model that frees you up
in order to you know kind of view things
to be able to do different tasks
additionally you're gonna have api's
that give you insight into things so
where is with you know physical data
centers you know someone actually might
have had to follow cables around in
order to figure out what's plugged into
what and what can actually communicate
with what whereas within the cloud
environment there's API calls that you
can make that can tell you what things
are actually able to talk to what and so
because of that that that then enables
you to create new tools and create
scanners that can do this so whereas
previously you know it might have only
been a task that you would go about
doing you know quarterly or something
like that to try and you know do a
physical assessment of some sort of an
understanding what was connected to what
now you can do these things hourly or
every minute or you know be able to get
alerts when any of these changes are
made so so that's kind of the the
biggest difference there is I think that
it's able to move you forward by
enabling you to accomplish some of these
things that you couldn't accomplish
previously what are the benefits of
cloud computing like whatever assets we
need to be considering when threat
modeling the cloud end and the
suitability of various providers a lot
of it a lot of it becomes pretty similar
as you had been doing in your data
centers yes I'm thinking of things like
productivity competitive advantage
control customer data reputation and
that sort of thing yeah yeah I so so
yeah with I mean a lot of these are all
just gonna be gains I think a lot of
benefits there so you know your
productivity increases you know
infinitely because now you don't have to
worry about you know trying to acquire
new systems or make sure your HVAC
system is going to be able to work with
this environment you know you're able to
just acquire new systems and
additionally you're able to leverage
services that are provided for you so
for example some of these cloud
providers provide in an elastic search
managed elastic search cluster for you
and so you no longer have to try and
maintain that yourself you know they
also provide a lot of database
capabilities for you for performing
snapshots or performing backups of the
data so so again you know these things
are taken care of for you
we're just going to move into a risks
and a countermeasures section we often
receive questions from software
engineers like here's a software
engineer do I really care about network
security and network security used to be
a slightly less of an issue for
suffering engineers than it is now like
a network security used to be and
primarily are the network
administrator's responsibility and now
that infrastructure and networks are
exposed by code with infrastructure and
configuration management tools such as
terraform ends of docker and others what
are your thoughts around the
responsibilities of network security now
falling in the laps of software
engineers I I think that it becomes
blended a lot of times now you know that
people have to have both of those skill
sets and so you you can't really be as
siloed into one of those categories
as he used to be and so you have to
understand you know what are the impacts
and and how to use some of these
different tools it's that you can you
know basically be able to move faster
and accomplish those different things
that the cloud enables you to do so an
example of that is you know being able
to stand up new services can be done you
know much faster and in cloud
environment whereas you know previously
you had to basically talk with your neck
rich engineer and make sure that
different ports and services could be
opened and you know potentially you had
to work around restrictions and
limitations of you know some of those
devices that you might have already had
in the environment and and you know
reorganize you know some of your subnets
and things like that depending on what
you're trying to accomplish whereas now
that can be done much faster and and
really you're not going to be as limited
as you were a lot of times with your
historical environments here we also had
a show out with James Turnbull around
terraform it was show number 289 I work
a lot with AWS which provides a security
abstraction model now we can create
objects like VP C's security groups and
roles ingress and egress rules access
control lists security roles attached to
instances roles consisting of sets of
profiles etc and then we have another
abstraction layer now with tools such as
tea reform which allow us to build these
resources our declaratively rather than
imperatively now this allows us to
conceptualize and build what we I want
with our understanding low-level
constructs such as firewalls IP tables
for example now how to configure Cisco
appliances in those sorts of things and
we're to put these only our network
topology now this seems too dumb the
skill set down a little bit of software
engineers it also allows our programmers
to come a network engineers in a sense
do you see this as a step forward or
step backwards or potentially both
in-house I you know I see this as a step
forward just because you know now you're
not gonna have you know some of the same
you know limitations that you had
previously and some of the I guess
inefficiencies that you had previously
whereas you know you might have had to
communicate with a whole lot of
different people and you know it was you
know potentially on what you're trying
to accomplish I could have been you know
big ordeals in in your organization to
try and open up different ports for
different reasons you know you were
limited and perhaps the number of IP
addresses that you had that were
publicly accessible and so now now a lot
of those restrictions are removed from
you so that you can you can really
accomplish a lot more a lot faster it
does present dangers though that you
know because you are moving faster that
now you know it does it does open up a
lot of those new risk to you though yep
the worse it is we're actually leaving
leaving some of these deep specialities
up to the security teams and networking
teams of the CSP so we're not having to
think about them so much but you like
you say they does open up new risks and
potentially new holes and a lack of
understanding I'm around the engineers
correct yeah so as customers of other
cloud we have little visibility of the
internal workings or implementations of
the infrastructural abstractions
provided to us Trust as a core concept
that we are yielding to our providers
all software has bugs right so how can
we be sure that our chosen CSP is fixing
their bugs quickly and not exposing us
to undue risk yeah so that that is one
of the dangers with cloud environments
but but I also view it as you know just
kind of a risk in danger that you have
with with any service that you're using
so you might imagine if you're using you
know the Windows operating system as
your base operating system in that case
you're relying on Microsoft to you know
maintain patches for that system and so
in in kind of the same way you know your
your cloud provider you're relying on
them to be patching potentially
operating systems that they're running
for you or potentially some of the other
services that you're running for you so
you so you always do have those risks to
some degree and know additionally you
know previously you might have been
using some type of data center where you
are leasing space somewhere your Lee
leasing racks from them so again you you
have kind of those you know potential
lack of visibility into some of the
actions they're doing there for you do
you have any sort of concrete examples
again I'm how we can get more visibility
into how the internal infrastructure
whether it even matters I mean what are
your thoughts around there yeah a lot of
the cloud providers they do a very good
job of trying to hide that from you and
so so becomes you know difficult or
impossible to know what's happening
underneath those abstraction layers that
you can't see you know in some ways you
might be able to try and you know try
and leak some of that information to
yourself but it it's really you know
it's really not something that you
should rely on basically they've
provided that abstraction to you and
they can change what's happening
underneath it anytime and so because
that it doesn't make a whole lot of
sense for you to try and understand
what's there if it potentially might
change under underneath you as long as
you're still getting the same service
and as long as you're still able to use
those abstraction layers and make kind
of your core base assumptions about
what's happening underneath you know you
don't really need to worry about what's
happening you know at you know
potentially like a network layer or you
know at a lower operating system layer
or something then what they've provided
and exposed to you
the way I think about it is it we're
trusting on the deep Security's so
they're deep our specialities and
security and what it does is it actually
moves our own focus of our development
teams to application security more so
would that be your sort of take on it
yeah exactly
you know previously whereas you might
have need to be an expert and you know
all sorts of different things and you
need to make sure that you know you were
maintaining patches of firmware and
things like that that now you know that
they're relieves some of that burden
from you a catastrophic data loss more
of an issue in the cloud than it was on
cream a due to the CSB
the customers just believing that the
CSPs will take care of it and
occasionally failing you know there
there have been a lot of you know news
reports of these different situations in
which you know people have exposed data
that they show
and they happen to have been using
different cloud providers and and I'm
not sure and I don't think it's entirely
due to the cloud providers you know in
some cases you know some of the user
interfaces that they've had have been a
little bit more confusing they've made a
couple things you know easier to do than
they should have done previously
however it's not you know a direct
failing of them in the sense that you
know they didn't it wasn't the cloud
provider that opened up this access you
know it was the the customer that opened
up you know some of this different
access however you know it is kind of on
the cloud provider to make you know
those those menus as understandable as
possible so that the you know the
customer understands the implications
better of what they're doing and I don't
think that that's probably always been
the case that you know the customers
haven't really realized that you know
for example that they're opening an s3
bucket to the world and exposing it to
everybody you know one of the one of the
prime examples of this is AWS when you
when you open up one of these s3 buckets
one of your options is you can expose it
to everybody or you can expose it to
authenticated users and so that was the
language that AWS used was they said
authenticated users and a lot of people
took that to mean that it was you know
users of their own AWS account that they
were opening this up to and so people
within their own company what they
didn't realize is that authenticated
users to AWS means anybody in AWS that
is authenticated so at any other company
or any other AWS account as long as they
had authenticated in they could access
these s3 buckets and so that was a big
failing of one of the cloud service
providers in in providing in an
understandable menu Tom yeah that's an
interesting one because I think if I saw
that I'm the nod I would immediately be
thinking about defense and depth and
I'll be thinking I'll be looking at that
and my first thoughts would be just what
you said there and then there has to be
another step in order to provide extra
authentication to that Pacific packet
exactly and I mean one you know there
are a lot of tools now that can help
with you know auditing for example you
know some of these misconfigurations
like publicly exposed as three buckets
which you know these tools they can't
they can't alert you and say this is you
know absolutely critical this is a thing
you need to fix because they're
obviously you know reasons why you would
open up an s3 bucket to be publicly
exposed like that for example a lot of
websites are hosted as s3 buckets my own
personal website for my company is
hosted as an s3 bucket and so you can't
you know immediately assume that just
because it's public that it's bad you
know there are there are legitimate
reasons for doing it but then things
that you can do to try and you know
implement defense-in-depth there's you
can you know potentially encrypt that
information that you're storing there
said even if it was misconfigured such
that this was a public publicly exposed
that an attacker or anybody else that
came across that data would only have
access to encrypted data and so you know
those are some of the precautions that
you can try and take have you got some
examples of hair we can what provide
that sort of encryption some of the
different service providers themselves
they'll you know provide different
capabilities for performing that
encryption for you so you know AWS with
at s3 buckets you know it can it can
accomplish some that for you however
there's always you know the the option
you can take to encrypt it yourself with
you know some type of other tool or free
third-party tool that exists out there
so so that that's kind of one of the
benefits and frustrations of the cloud
is that there's always going to be many
of these different options for you to
take you know you can you can either go
all in and you know continuously use
more and more of the different cloud
service providers offerings which you
know has the you know kind of you know
difficulty or frustration that it's
continuously locking you into that cloud
provider making it more and more
difficult for you to switch cloud
providers or you know increases the risk
that if anything would ever happen in
that cloud provider you know that could
be you know more of a a greater impact
to your business if you're heavily
locked into them and for example they're
your cloud provider goes bankrupt or or
some other type of incident happens to
them you know or you could go the other
route of just you know using all of your
own tools and using the bare minimum of
what the cloud service provider offers
and so that reduces that lock-in but at
the same time it also means that you're
not going to be
the you know move as efficiently as you
would if you were to use all the
different cloud service providers
offerings yeah it's a real balancing act
doesn't it I mean I mean what are some
of the things that we actually have to
weigh out there I I mean you know as an
example I mentioned previously like the
elasticsearch clusters you know there
there are offerings for that from some
of the service providers and and so you
know again another kind of frustration
that you can run into is if you're using
one of those services you really become
more and more dependent on that cloud
service provider and how they're running
it for you there there might be ways in
which they will be unwilling to
configure it that you might be able to
configure it yourself you might not have
access to certain logs or you know
visibility into resource usage that you
would have otherwise if you were running
it yourself and so those are some of the
you know difficulties that you can run
into but but at this point time I mean
there there's you know all sorts of
different cloud service offerings AWS
just had their big conference of the
year called reinvent in which they
announced a number of new service
offerings and so it it becomes very
difficult even to just keep track of
what they're what all they're providing
you know I think a lot of people and
they think of the cloud you know all
they're thinking of is that basically
they can run some vm up there that that
that's what is you know being granted to
you is the ability to ssh into a system
and install your you know your software
on there but nowadays there there's a
whole variety of you know different
service offerings that exist in addition
to you know different queueing software
different database software that's all
being managing to run for you if you
want to so want to talk a little bit
about how we can evaluate if using any
given CSP is going to provide a high
enough level of security for us in our
customers so we're going to discuss
techniques we can use to compare
different csps offerings and whether or
not they fit for our purpose so feel
free to mention any that you think of as
we work through the following this what
are your thoughts on keeping signed
audit logs on you eyes and api's I I
mean I leverage those heavily in in a
lot of detections and monitoring that I
do just because you know you can see not
only not only does it give you the
insight into what has historically
happened in your environment on purpose
from from your own employees when you
know perhaps they were starting up new
instances and so you know that this can
be helpful to the billing department to
understand you know who was running
these new instances and you know gives
insight and two windows happened and you
know you can kind of correlate that back
to why that happened to some degree but
but then you know it also is very
important for being detect you know
potentially attackers in your
environment and so that this is where
you know logging becomes very important
is seeing you know some of those access
denied so not only be able to see what
did happen in your environment but also
being able to see what was attempted to
have happen in your environment and so
that's that's where a lot of that
logging can also be useful for example
if you know you've implemented these
privileges across your different users
that you have in your environment and
someone started trying to use you know
services or access resources they didn't
have permission to you know that could
be there could be legitimate reasons for
that but it also could be because
perhaps you know they're the credentials
of that employee were compromised and an
attacker was trying to look around and
investigate inside your environment yeah
yeah there's quite a few tools that can
help us there as well and we're just
going to talk a little bit those I'm
closer to the end of the show so um so
AWS has some cloud trail right I guess
it's what you would primarily use for
audit logs correct yeah so AWS has cloud
trail which is going to cord all the
different API calls and gives you
information about the action that was
taken for example you know I was trying
to spin up a new ec2 instance or
creating a new s3 bucket and it tells
you who did it tells you win tells you
you know whether or not they had
multi-factor authentication when they
were trying to perform this action but
but it also has some limitations and so
some of those for example is it doesn't
give you insight into the the data level
actions that occur so as an example you
could see that a new s3 bucket was
created but you could not see what data
was read from that bucket or written to
that bucket AWS has recently made a you
know an option for you to get some
insight into that but historically that
not been visible to you additionally you
could see that a new ec2 instance was
created but you could not see you know
who SSH tin to that instance you could
not see you know any of your you know
logs from your different services that
were running on that instance so it
doesn't give you that type of visibility
additionally cloud trail has always had
a 15 minute delay to to the recordings
of the logs that it does which means
that you can never have true real-time
you know recording or monitoring
alerting and you know potentially
remediation of things as they happen you
know you always have the situation or an
attacker if they started doing an attack
of any sort they had 15 minutes where
they knew that that that the defenders
would be completely blind to any of that
attack AWS has recently kind of made
some changes via what's called cloud
watch logs where you can get some
insight into some of the cloud trail
data but you still don't get it all the
insight into what's happening with that
cloud trail data you still have to wait
that 15 minutes to see that the logs
when they appear in your s3 bucket which
is where they're recorded do security is
everyone's problem to solve and
responsibility to understand at the
O'Reilly software architecture
conference we look at how an
understanding of threat and risk can
help teams to think broadly about
security issues and solutions join us in
New York February 25th through 28th
visit software architecture con-com to
register and save 20% by using code ser
yes so for finer grained things like you
said who is actually searching into your
VM or whatever else you know like
basically just finer grained events now
what do we use for that do we have to
set something up on the actual machine
oh yeah so so on if it if it is for you
know monitoring SSH
logins you're going to have to set
something up on that system to record
that and so AWS for example they do
provide an agent that you could run on
that system however you could also you
know run whatever other agent you have
out there
whether it's you know logstash or that
yes exactly
any other type of monitoring solution
you you could set up there but but again
you know it's gonna be a thing that
you're gonna have to know that this is
where a limitation of a SS is
responsibilities you know changes
where's this is a thing that is
happening on the surface itself and
therefore you know that's gonna be your
responsibility to do that monitoring so
hem nice a space are encrypting all
comes between their servers in and their
other components within their data
centers and also with their service
providers can you think of it any so so
that that is one of the concerns as you
mentioned earlier about you know those
layers of the distractions where well
III don't think the different service
providers have said you know or at least
not given specifics in terms of you know
where all they're doing that ain't that
potential encryption you know are they
doing it you know within the data center
between you know different machines are
they doing it you know between different
regions that they have you know so so as
an example like AWS has the concept of
availability zones where if you have us
East one basically encompasses more or
less the entire US eastern seaboard so
you don't know you know between the
different cities is that data being
encrypted I don't think they've they've
ever made those claims or you know you'd
have to try and dig through a lot of
documentation to try and find that out
yeah so what are your thoughts on how we
can actually improve it and potentially
I'm safeguard ourselves from
eavesdropping and that sort of thing
yeah so so again you know this is a
thing where you could set it up yourself
where you could set up you know mutual
TLS authentication between you know all
of your different services there there
there are you know some some areas
between these different cloud service
providers that you can hopefully make
some assumptions for example
specifically within you know what's
called your VP sees that that's going to
be hopefully encrypted between there but
again you know it depends on how much
you really trust that the cloud service
provider is really accomplishing all of
that for you
here so I'm so between the likes of our
survivalist technologies in it I mean do
we have any show of providing encryption
I again I mean I think the the only the
the only thing that we we do know is
that so far I haven't heard publicly
about anybody you know exploiting that
in any way and in hope and I would
imagine that that would be you know a
big news event if you did find out that
you know someone was able to to sniff
some of that traffic and use it in you
know different ways or if they were to
leapfrog between boxes you know that's
one of the biggest threats you know I
read I read a paper from from a cyber
insurance company once that was you know
just discussing like what what do they
view as kind of the the hurricane level
events in cyber insurance and and one of
the things they talked about was the
hypervisor escape that would allow them
without a loud attacker to jump from
different instances within a cloud
service provider you know whereas you
know you might be one customer with your
own instances and then suddenly an
attacker is able to go through the cloud
service provider in order to get access
to your instances there you know that's
one of the biggest scares for a lot of
people I see a space providing customers
access to infrastructure logs at all and
what does that access look like if so
and how much is filtered before we get
our hands on them again you know you
have access to the logs about you know
the infrastructure that you're creating
for yourself in terms of you know
instances you stand up or changes that
you're making to the firewalls yourself
but you're only getting access access to
that level of information you know you
don't get access to anytime a new rack
is put into a data center somewhere in
AWS is environment you don't get access
to you know whenever new customers or
anything like that is you know gonna get
put next to you you know on you know the
same potentially the same system as you
you know just running in different VMs
on that same system you won't ever get
access to any of that information yeah
so so do you have any idea of how much
is actually getting filtered out before
we get our hands on them I I don't know
I mean it's really it really just comes
down to looking and seeing like
what information they're providing -
which is again you know just the actions
that you're taking and you know just
making assumptions that there's a lot of
other things happening behind the scenes
but but again hopefully like none of
those things are gonna impact you
hopefully they've made the precautions
necessary so that you know if any of
those changes do happen behind the
scenes that they aren't going to impact
you you know you do periodically have
these events where you know AWS makes or
you know different cloud service
providers make mistakes in you know
potentially configuration changes that
they're making or code updates that they
make and you know it ends up you know
accidentally shutting down whole regions
are shutting down you know availability
zones in different ways and and again a
lot of them are pretty bad about
updating customers in any way about that
you really you really only find out
about it when you know something goes
wrong and you know you're wondering why
it happens and you you potentially check
a status page or something like that and
you find out that you know that it's
gone down you know some of the cloud
service providers have been pretty bad
about updating their own certain status
pages though so you know you you've had
an incident a number of months ago where
you know s3 went down us beast one for
for everybody and AWS never updated
their status page for it and everybody's
like it shows green but clearly it is
broken for everybody right now so what
happens with their data when we
terminate our accounts were their
provider or migrate to other providers
so the data are behind the scenes on
most of the cloud service providers
should all be zeroed out immediately
after after you terminate instances
they're had in the early days of cloud
they hadn't been ziering out this
information and there was you know some
ghosting of different sorts of some of
the prior customers data for four there
was one cloud service provider that was
unfortunately not taking that precaution
but but nowadays they they should all be
zeroing out that information
additionally like I said earlier with
you know physical hard drives and things
like that once those hard drives come to
an end of life you know they they have a
process of destroying those before they
even leave the data centers so are they
zero yet like camps are sections of the
disks or the entire disk it hopefully
should be all the useful data on there
but but I don't I don't know
you know specifics of how they're
accomplishing it you know in theory this
is a this is a place where we just have
to put place our trust on them that they
are zeroing out all the information I
guess different customs will be sharing
disks right correct
yeah so I mean once once you start up an
instance you know you would it's very
unlikely that you know you are the first
person to be running on that hardware
chances are another customer has been
there before you and another customer
will be there after you yeah so it'll be
interesting to know whether they're
actually zeroing out just your stuff or
whether they're not zeroing it out at
all until all customers are off that
particular disk yeah do we know who can
view the data we store in the cloud
CSP employees in what chicksand controls
do the major CS B's have in place to
make sure that this data cannot be read
or exfiltrated yeah so so again this is
a this is an area where I think most of
the most of the cloud providers will
state the you know that they're not
giving access to their employees of any
sort you know being able to see any type
of visibility however you know I I would
be surprised if they're not being able
to see some you know logging information
specifically things that that as data is
leaving your environment you know for
example AWS will alert you if your
systems start port scanning other
systems out there on the internet you
know though they'll tell you that one of
your systems is potentially compromised
so they'll try and alert you of that and
you know they're they're doing that you
know not only because it's it's nice of
them to let you know that a system is
compromised but also you know they don't
want to have you know hack systems
running in their environment and deal
with the you know potential
repercussions of getting blacklisted by
different services for that reason so um
so they will detect
some of those things but again that
that's only gonna be things that are
happening as data is leaving your
environment so it's so logging that they
can see as network traffic is leaving
out of the environment they shouldn't be
able to see what what is actually
running in your ec2 instances you know
they shouldn't be able to have access to
memory dumps or anything like that and
and you know we think that you know that
that's true just because there there
have been a lot of times when customers
have asked for memory dumps of their
systems and AWS has responded that you
know they're not capable of it you know
or different cloud service providers say
they can't do that that they have a lot
of precautions in place and so that's
what you know kind of gives us the
confidence that that okay they really
don't have access you know because in
some cases it's you know very large
customers that have a lot of money and
very big support contracts where you
think that you know the cloud service
providers would would be able to you
know make some be able to go out of
their way or change their rules a little
bit for you know some of the large sums
of money that you know some of these
customers are potentially willing to
throw around and in the cloud service
writer still will not make any changes
to that those policies or any csps
standing out you I can think of that are
doing a decent job of the
responsibilities in helping you know
potential customers understand we are
the lines of separation are in terms of
the shared responsibility model I mean I
think all the different cloud service
providers do have some types of
documents that they provide so you know
AWS is the environment that I work with
the most and so you know I read through
a lot of their documents and and they
have a document specifically about that
that's shared responsibility model and
and I imagine that the different clouds
were the other cloud service providers
such as Microsoft Azure and Google cloud
and some of the others that they're also
providing those as well I see quite a
bit of the documentation in it but I'm
just not sure how much of that's
actually making it to the likes of the
sea levels yeah
and I mean it always becomes a
frustration that they're there
potentially is a lot of this
documentation out there but you know it
might be so overwhelming or it might be
you know kind of difficult to understand
what are the right documents to read a
lot of AWS is documenting
for their different services ends up
being you know hundreds of pages long
and so trying to find those nuggets of
information that you're actually looking
for in there can become difficult is it
a better idea to actually build the
stuff into the interface because people
just generally only read Docs if they
have to write yeah but they have to use
the UI and the api's and that sort of
thing potentially building some
information around this into those sort
of interfaces what are your thoughts
around there yeah I mean again that
that's gonna be you know a difficult
usability problem to try and to try and
present the user with you know the
things that they need to know the things
that you know they want to be able to do
and learn and know about the product but
not overwhelm them and not you know make
it just you know too difficult with too
much text too too many buttons on there
you know we've all seen those interfaces
where it's just you know a you know
overwhelming to to you especially as a
beginner user but then you know as you
become a power user some of those
environments you know might not offer
enough of the buttons enough of the text
you know as as you become more
comfortable with those tools so just
gonna move into a bit of a section on
the differences between cloud service
providers and in-house so what are some
of the aspects that are more secure in
the cloud then in-house can you think of
any concrete examples as we as we
mentioned you know taking care of a lot
of the physical security I think that
the cloud service providers can do that
a lot better than then a lot of you know
you know I guess private entities can
can accomplish that themselves you know
it depends on you know what are the
entities you're looking at or you're
looking at you know a mom-and-pop or you
know just a brand new startup that only
has a couple of employees or are you
looking at you know potentially much
larger you know company that that has a
much larger workforce and can accomplish
those things you know so especially for
for you know the small startups you know
they'd only have a few employees you
know the cloud service writers are gonna
be able to accomplish a lot of these
things a lot better than them you know
specifically around things like you know
having you know guards that are Manning
these these centers 24/7 and having
processes in place for all these
different things you know they're gonna
be able to accomplish that a lot better
things like you know segmentation of
duties you know if you only have you
know a company of three people there's
not a whole lot of segmentation of
duties that you can really accomplish
there you know where's you know once you
have hundreds of employees then you can
start you know splitting up those
responsibilities in different ways
better but we have heard you know that
some of these cloud service providers
you know they do have you know that
since they are bigger companies there
they've hired a lot of experts in
different fields and those experts have
different you know friends in different
areas that they're doing research and
and you know friends and governments and
things like that that you know
potentially some of the cloud service
providers are getting access to
information about you know things like
vulnerabilities before potentially of
the larger public is getting access to
some of those things a CSP is a test
with taking a cue of aspects such as
just general infrastructure hardware
hosting continuously hardening
components and infrastructure patching
components only visible to the CSP a
network firewall routes and rules of the
CSP s core infrastructure and network
component logging and network intrusion
detection system so in regular
penetration testing do those
organizations contemplating in-house
cloud solutions need to consider all of
these air specs I mean they still showed
that they still should undergo things
like you know pen tests and things like
that just because you do need to expose
the different areas of of your
responsibility for security in those
environments that that aren't being
handled by those different cloud service
providers so you should still have
things like network intrusion detection
and part of this is because you know
that the cloud service providers they
they might be accomplishing some of
these things they might be performing
some of these things but they might not
be giving you that visibility and
insight into what they're finding so you
know they might have you know network
intrusion detection of some sort but it
potentially is only gonna be for their
own systems and it's not going to be
detecting things for your systems and
they might have you know different
different levels in which they would
inform you about these so for example I
mentioned earlier about how I you know
they'll detect port scanning and be able
to alert you about that well it depends
on
know when they're gonna be alerting you
about that you know they might not they
might take a while to alert you they
might know they might only alert you
when you know someone else on the
Internet complains about it they might
not alert you as quickly you know and
they might not give you the specifics of
the information that you need otherwise
so it still is very important to do
things like you know the monitoring to
be able to do pen tests to be able to do
things like that across your environment
so how can we be better prepared for
csps being forced to give up our and our
customers data to governing authorities
and others without our permission or
even knowledge in many cases does this
just come down to using more crypto or
what else can we do yeah so I mean there
you do want to make sure depending on I
guess you know your views of of
different countries governments where
your data is being held at and so you
know you can ensure that that it's being
used and you know maintained only in
specific countries locations so you can
do that but then additionally you know
your other fallback is going to have to
be on things like encryption to try and
protect that but again you know it be
it's a very hard problem to ensure that
the data that you have you know on on
one of these cloud service providers if
you are keeping it in any type of
unencrypted manner because ultimately
you want to be able to use that
information there to try and try and
ensure that it can't be you know I guess
read by that cloud service provider in
in any way like it it becomes a very
hard problem there's not really any good
solutions to so I'm just moving on to
I'm a couple of questions around some
other risks and CSPs provide many
security enhancing services and features
most of which I see software developers
and people above them in the old chair I
think of as inconveniences here can we
encourage our developers and others to
use the security features and more
security by default or any other ideas I
think I think one of the ways you know
it always helps to be able to present
people with different checklists and be
able to you know give them a scoring on
how well they're doing in there
and so there's become a number of tools
you can run they'll just do simple scans
across your environment to look for
certain you know whether or not certain
security features have been enabled or
whether or not there's been miss
configurations that have happened so for
example you know it'll be able to detect
you know which of your users have
multi-factor authentication enabled for
them
or whether or not you're using password
complexity policies you know so it can
it can make some of those checks for you
or whether or not you have logging
turned on for example the cloud trail
logs or some of the other logging
options that exist for a to us so so
that's I think that that's one of the
ways in which you can go about that is
you know run one of these tools see what
you know your your output is from it and
then be able to prevent present that to
potentially management or others to be
able to show them like hey look it we
were we have a score on here you know of
you know 15 out of 20 and if we want to
get you know the full you know 100
percent for our score then we need to do
these you know additional steps for
ourselves any thoughts or security
concerns around surveillance
technologies that look new or there's
software engineers we need to be
thinking about you know again there
still are the risk that you know behind
the scenes it still is you know an
operating system that that exists out
there in the world that potentially has
different types of vulnerabilities in it
your software itself you know is going
to still have different vulnerabilities
in it potentially and so so you still
have to be you know mindful of these
different things I think a lot of people
just assume that you know as long as
they're running its server list that you
know potentially it's going to run too
quickly for for an attacker to be able
to exploit you know because a lot of
them can only run for maybe five minutes
at a time but you know an attacker can
still maintain persistence in different
ways in those environments and attackers
are getting better about being able to
automate their own tools so that they
can accomplish things in an automated
fashion without having to you know be
hands-on keyboard as they're you know
trying to attack different things so so
I mean that that's just kind of the the
biggest thing there is that that it
still is a lot of the same issues but
but it's just you know changing how how
those things are
going to get attacked in the future and
how you know you can trying to defend
against these things I'm guess I'm I'm
trying to dig for some examples I'm a on
some of the different service
technologies and in what we need to be
thinking about I mean can you think of
any examples yeah so so I mean there's
like AWS has their lambda service which
is going to be there their servers less
technology there and with lambda usually
what you're gonna do is you're gonna
sign what's called an iam role to to
those different functions that you that
you've built up there and those IM roles
allow you to take actions in the AWS
environment for example it might give
them the ability to read from an s3
bucket it might give them you know some
other types of you know capabilities and
and with that IM role you can limit it
down you can restrict it to say only
this woman s3 bucket is the only one i
want to be read from and potentially
only within this directory within that
s3 bucket however a lot of people might
you know miss configure that IM role and
just give it access to all the s3
buckets you know it just be easier for
them to just say you know s3 star is the
privilege that you give in so that gives
it access to all the s3 buckets you know
and that also gives them the ability to
read to write you know potentially
delete information in there and so
that's you know that that's one of the
concerns there's if that serverless
function was exploited then you know the
attacker has those full privileges to to
attack all those different things
additionally a lot of your you know a
lot of your server list code is gonna be
like your other code that you have in
which case you know you have different
secrets in that code that you need to
manage correctly and so these secrets
are gonna be things like you know api
keys or potentially passwords things
like that to give them access to
different databases or other services
that exist out there and and so you
still need to be able to protect those
different secrets and so that you know
because again if that if that technology
was exploited in some way the attacker
would have access to those secrets so
you know you need to make sure that
you're protecting those you're able to
roll those quickly if they ever do get
compromised so so those those become all
the different you know
um difficulties that you have is it's
really a lot of the same ones but it's
just you know applied in a slightly
different way if you're a software
engineer and you are you working away at
one of these service technologies or
anything basically in the card it's just
like right let's get it working right
and we'll work about the city well I'm
thinking about I'm here we're gonna
secure it later so a lot of the time
these things actually get neglected in
they get left quite quite open exactly
and so that that becomes where it's
important to audit you know what those
different you know I am policies that
have been applied but these different
resources are and and using the cloud
trail logs that we mentioned earlier you
know you can start using those logs
additionally with with the policy that
exists currently to understand what of
the capabilities that resource has that
is actually using or not using and
therefore start you know trimming it
down and restricting in different ways
so you know by looking at the cloud
trail logs you can see oh hey it's it's
only ever using you know this one s3
bucket therefore I should restrict it
down to only accessing that one bucket
and not give it access to all buckets
can you think of any of the of the
features that I Wasi example provide to
help us with secrets and storage of
secrets yeah so so there is a service
called kms that mu s provides which is a
key management system and there there's
been some open source projects that are
built on top of that for example cred
stash uses kms
but then AWS also has I think it's
called SSM is the name of their service
which is which is essentially cred stash
but just kind of a managed version that
ATS is providing to you and so what
these allow you to do is this allows you
to to when you give an eye-roll to a
different resource for example your
lambda there your lambda function what
you can do is you can tell it okay you
can access you know this key this you
know one secret and so it can access
that then your your other functions
cannot also access that same secret so
you can you can divvy this up and break
it up into different ways that some
functions can access some secrets and
some can access others and so that's
that's really the the power
that one of the services that the
different cloud providers can offer to
you yes it's it's coming back to the
least privileged concept and defense and
deep exactly yeah and I mean the biggest
benefit of doing the site of thing is
keeping those secrets outside of code
you know where you know the code
potentially could get leaked or the code
at-least know you know a lot of
companies have just one single repo of
code that they're that they're sharing
across all their developers and so you
know if you have hundred developers all
your hundred developers are gonna have
access to that code and chances are
unfortunately one of those developers
he's gonna upload all that code to
github at some point you know or or you
might have a contractor and you're gonna
end up you know that they might do it by
accident or you know someone might get
compromised one of their laptops gets
compromised and now you know the
attacker has access to that data there
you know I think a lot of people don't
realize that like especially source code
ends up getting shared probably more
widely than people expect it to you know
anytime that you know you need to do any
type of audit or something like that
chances are you might end up having to
share your source code it was some other
third party in some way and so you want
to make sure those secrets are not being
held in that source code as you
potentially you know hand it off to
somebody yeah it's more made of so you
created flaws as a free online
capture-the-flag tutorial to help
recognize common misconfigurations and
gotchas and AWS can you talk a little
bit more about this yeah so so this was
about a year ago that I created it and
it was really you know I was I was
running companies security at the time
we had a DevOps guide we had some
developers and I wanted to you know
provide them some training on you know
some of the potential gotchas in an AWS
environment and so these were things
like you know s3 buckets that have been
exposed or you know one thing that a lot
of people aren't aware of is there
there's kind of a magic IP address in
the different cloud service providers
that's 169.254 dot 169.254 and if you
can access that you
can get credentials for that resource
that can basically take over the IAM
role of that service and so this has
happened in the past where you know
people would run some type of proxy
service on AWS and it would end up
someone would use that proxy service to
access that magic IP address and get
those credentials you know or in various
other ways people have accessed that IP
address and so that was another one of
the levels and flaws and so this is what
I wanted to do is just kind of show my
own developers my own team you know what
are some of the concerns that that we
have and and you know I looked through
hacker one and other you know
repositories of you know bug bounties
and things like that
trying try and identify you know
different ways that companies have have
either been hacked or you know had bug
bounties awarded against them and so so
looked up those things and basically
built up kind of a game that had you
actually perform those attacks you could
actually see what it looks like from the
attackers perspective and see honestly
how easy some of these attacks are to
perform it when when things are
misconfigured like this and so so with
that was able to show you know my team
what those different problems are and
included in there for every single level
basically gave you no hints along the
way that describe you know how this is
happening and then at the end of the
level I basically say this is what the
MIS configuration was here's some
examples of you know companies that had
this Mis configuration and you'll be
able to give that that information to
people so they're they're better aware
of those issues and I figured as long as
I was releasing it you know from my own
my own team I was able to do it in such
a way that I could release it publicly
to people so so others could play along
with it and so so it's free at flaws
cloud you know you can access it you can
play it any time and be able to go
through and if you don't want to
actually be hands on keyboard and
actually perform that attacks yourself
you can just click through the hints and
it'll you know be able to click through
one level to the next level without
actually having to do anything yourself
and so so it's been you know a lot of
I've received a lot of feedback from
people both on Twitter and you know
emails where people you know said it's
been useful that they've trained you
know their team with it that
you know it might be college students or
something that we're learning AWS for
the first time and and they've used that
to try and learn some of the things
about AWS before they started you know
actually using the services so they were
prepared for you know potential mistakes
that they might make in that environment
and so you know in the first um and the
first month like 30,000 people had
already visited the site and so it was
it was way bigger than I ever expected
like for something that is as niche as
AWS security you know I didn't expect as
much you know positive responses from
people or as many people just seeing it
as actually did yeah that's awesome hey
how many levels does a hey um I think
it's six levels the first couple they're
gonna be related to as three buckets and
then and then it gets into some of the
other different issues that can occur
via KHOU are you on the purple squad
security podcast recently discussing
detecting intruders on AWS can you give
us a bit of a rundown on what was
discussed yeah so so I'm not podcast um
I discussed no basically some of the
different ways some of the different
logs that exist on a DBS and you know
some of the ways you can collect and
monitor that information and what to
look for you know more specifically in
there and really comes down to you know
being able to look for access denied
when you have implemented these
privileges across your environment you
know one one of the things that I did
with flaws was I was not only releasing
it as kind of a tutorial to my own
employees but one of the reasons I
released it publicly was I was using it
more or less as like a honeypot to be
able to see what does it look like when
someone tries to attack an environment
because in in flaws what I'm doing is
I'm giving I'm giving random people on
the internet access keys to my AWS
environment so they're actually have you
know credentials of some sort they're
very restricted you know so they're they
can't do anything that impacts the game
they're you know they're not able to run
ec2 instances to mine Bitcoin or
anything like that in my environment so
I'm not you know I'm not being charged a
bunch of money for it but with it you
know I was able to look in the logs and
see what are the types of different
things that they're doing and
and you know try and look for things of
interest in there so so one thing that I
thought was you know somewhat
interesting was I was just that of
people that actually like played the
game hands on keyboard actually you know
were using the command-line against it
there was about a thousand people that
that really you know were weren't just
you know clicking through the the web
tutorial but we're actually you know
playing the game and of those thousand
people there were about a thousand
different user agents of their tools
when they were hitting my services and
so I thought that was really interesting
so these aren't browser user agents
these are the command lines user agents
so it's gonna be like a AWS CLI and it's
gonna give you the Linux version they're
using or if they happen to be on Windows
or some other operating system so it's
somewhat similar to your browser CLI but
it you know gives you the version of
Python that's being used by the CLI and
and some things like that and so I
thought that was you know it's it's not
really a good detection but that was a
thing of interest from the tool I've
also leaked a number of keys on des
services like github and pastebin things
like that just to just to see like what
what happens when an attacker tries to
get access to those and in cases like
that you know a lot of times they're
using tor or some of their type of proxy
in order to access your you know your
services and so so that's the thing to
look for is to see is someone using tor
with your access keys chances are you're
real developers and you're real devops
guys aren't using tor when they're you
know doing real work and so that that's
a thing that you can look for and in AWS
actually just recently after a
conference then released a new service
called guard duty and and so this
service is it's just four dollars a
month which is pretty cheap and that'll
actually look for things such as service
keys using that that are being accessed
from behind tor nodes ok cool you also
wrote an article recently on potential
gaps and suggested Amazon Web Services
security policies for MFA now what
couldn't us do you have to share with
their listeners from this yeah so so
this was I was working with a client and
so in this case it happened to be duo
security that I was working with and so
discovered kind of an issue with a
policy that AWS had
in that they had posted online that they
had been advocating to to their
customers for a while and this was a
policy that was supposed to enforce
multi-factor authentication on on the
different users of a native US
environment and so you know the thought
was is that you know you you turn on MFA
but AWS doesn't actually enforce MFA
when it's being used for access keys so
even if you have in an MFA device it's
not actually going to require you to use
that and so what this policy does is it
requires the user to actually use that
and it was supposed to have some some I
guess gaps in it in order to allow you
know a user to be able to change their
password be able to change their MFA
device that they got a new one and be
able to do some things like that and and
so which is really useful for things
like onboarding you know you don't want
to have to have you know one
administrator you know helping people
change their password every time they
want to change it or anything like that
you know so it was supposed to help with
that but unfortunately it had some what
can best be described as vulnerabilities
in it and so so what these would allow
an attacker to do is if they did a
compromised someone's access keys and
those access keys were supposed to have
this policy on it to require an MFA
device what the attacker could do is
they could actually use one of the gaps
in the policy to remove the MFA device
that currently exists by the user and
add in the own an attackers own MFA
device and so they could add in their
own MFA device now the now there is an
MFA device associated with that customer
the attacker can can then make use of
whatever other privileges they had
because then they can just you know
punch in the the code for that MFA
device because the attacker owns that
MFA device now so that was really the
big thing was it was allowing you to
just completely bypass their
multi-factor authentication policy and
this set escaped you know a lot of
people over the years you know and AWS
themselves had put up that policy and so
so what what I was able to do with my
client was you know work with the ADA be
our security team in order to get it
fixed and they sent out emails to
different customers to inform their
customers you know that this this change
had been made to make them aware of
these problems that is that had existed
with it um so that was it was an
interesting experience and we ended up
putting up a blog post about that
afterwards nice I've got links to all
these in the show notes as well I know
of in have documented them a little bit
as our security monkey in the cloud
chapter of my second book now for the
listeners can you talk a bit about I'm
security monkey and also yeah being base
stream alert yeah so so these are these
are two pretty separate tools that are
through each helping you mostly with
your AWS environment so so security
monkey nowadays also works with Google
cloud in order to be able to detect
issues with that and and I think they're
they're also trying to expand it to to
misconfigurations beyond just a cloud
service offerings but also things like
like if you have a github enterprise
that that are they're also putting in
some checks there or to be able to tech
misconfigurations there but but what
security monkey does is this was a tool
released by Netflix um a number of years
ago and a lot of a lot of people that do
DevOps work might be familiar with
things like chaos monkey which was
another Netflix tool which would go
ahead and kill different instances to
ensure that you had that availability
that things would restart you know
automatically for you but what security
monkey does is this is another project
of theirs and it will actually go ahead
and check different AWS environments
that you have and look for things like
exposed s3 buckets or I am policies that
that are very permissive and allow a lot
of things or access keys that haven't
been rolled in over ninety days or you
know all sorts of different checks I you
know I think at this point I imagine
there's at least dozens of checks in
there you know if not a hundred checks
there there's tons of different things
that and they're adding to it all the
time so it's a very active project still
and and what this does is it's running
continuously and so every single hour
it's making these checks and it can
email you when it finds new things and
it can show you a diff it can also you
know be able to show you all the
currently open issues that haven't been
justified yet but so that's the other
thing that does is it provides you a
whole web you
you can log into you can search through
and find all these issues and you can go
ahead and justify them and it does you
know allow some role based access
control where you could have some people
that only have viewing permissions and
some people that have the ability to
comment on issues and some people that
have the ability to actually justify
those issues and close them out and so
that's that's a great tool that it's
been around for a while and is
phenomenal for be able to detect all
sorts of issues in an environment and so
there are some other tools that are more
geared towards you know pen testers that
are gonna be like one-time scan and so
this would be a tool like a prowler is
an example of that and it just don't do
a one-time scan and they'll give you you
know that report where as what security
monkey is doing is it's just
continuously running in your environment
and be able to detect things and so
that's a great tool and then stream
alert what it does is it's it's
monitoring your logs in it I used it
primarily for things like monitoring
cloud trail logs but it can be used
against any type of logging service and
so you know Airbnb they were they built
it originally you know for their web
server logs and just all the logs that
they're had coming in and stream alert
is is very focused on AWS and so it's
using Kinesis and it's using some
lambdas you know and and some other
services of AWS and so it very much ties
you into that environment so you're not
gonna want to use stream alert for you
know Microsoft Azure or Google cloud or
anything like that
so so it ties you into that environment
but because it's you know serverless and
it's it's taking advantage of the things
that eight of us is providing it's able
to work as basically a sim that that
just scales infinitely for you and you
don't have to you know manage it you
don't have to try and keep up with it
too much there's a little bit of care
and feeding that you might have to do
especially as you start you know using
it more aggressively and more heavily
but it's very hands-off and and it's
able to work very quickly on things as
well and so that that's a great tool and
that's all basically all of your alerts
or detections for things is all it all
exists as code that you check into you
know your own git repo and so so with
that you know you're able to have a
history
you know why you why you created this
rule and exactly what that rule is in
any comments that you want to include in
that and who created that rule and so
it's a great tool from that perspective
and that and that's really moving you in
the direction of using you know
basically get to maintain your whole
detections and monitoring the learning
framework and that has a lot of benefits
to it and so that's a great example the
tool that allows you to do that cool do
you have any interesting personal
projects or events that you've got on
the guy currently Scott um I do actually
for for a client right now I'm working
on a tool to visualize AWS environments
and so so this would be a tool that
would allow you to basically see the
different ec2 instances and what
security groups what what network
accesses are available between security
groups and so this is a project that
will be open sourcing here pretty soon
because I'm doing a collaboration with a
client and so that's gonna be awesome
and it you know we have plans of taking
it a step further in the future because
there are some tools that exist out
there on the market that are commercial
tools that allow you to visualize things
like this but we have plans to also take
it and be able to visualize some of your
iam permissions that you have so so as
we mentioned earlier about lambdas that
have access to all your ass three
buckets even though you might have the
expectation that it only has access to
you know one or two buckets this tool
will be able to help you visualize and
see that and I think you know we've
already discovered you know as we've
been using the tool you know it's really
helped us understand the environment of
my client a lot better because now they
now it's not only as code it's not just
a web UI you know that they're clicking
around in the AWS console and they're
trying to read text in order to
understand their environment now it's
actually visually representing it for
them yes so when's it gonna be open
source scope that that should be in the
next hopefully few weeks we'll see how
you know we still have to try and test
it out and make sure it's it's ready for
a more public audience but but I would
imagine so probably sometime in January
cool so so due to time shifting we may
or may not get that link into the show
notes okay yeah
okay so so what have we are not
discussed that we really should have
discussed can you think of anything no
I'm good
Scott thanks for joining us today it's
been educational and fun yeah thank you
for having me this has been great for
software engineering right yeah this was
Kim kata listen up software engineers
what was the last time you proposed a
product change that was really listened
to how often does your code shift to
production
same day within minutes when was the
last time you actually wanted to go to
work
at ultimate software this could be your
new normal and with offices in Florida
Georgia and California what are you
waiting for visit ultimate software comm
slash careers today and start making a
difference tomorrow
ultimate software people first thanks
for listening to se radio an educational
program brought to you by Triple E
software magazine for more about the
podcast including other episodes visit
our website at SC radio net to provide
feedback you can comment on each episode
on the website or reach us on LinkedIn
Facebook Twitter or through our slack
channel at SC radio.com you can also
email us at team at SC - radio net this
and all other episodes of se radio is
licensed under Creative Commons license
2.5 thanks for listening